# **Arizona Claude Edwards**



Washington, DC 202 888 5614

arizonace@gmail.com



				Skills
Skill	YoE	Engagement	Rating	Description/Keywords
C++	10+	~~~	****	STL, ATL, MFC, also: FCL, C++/CLI, OWL, etc.
C#/DotNet	8		****	Windows Forms, DLLs, Interop, Web ASP.NET
Python	3		<b>★★★☆</b>	PEP-008, multiprocessing, .NET and C++ Interop
JavaScript	3		<b>★★★☆</b>	Web, Bloomberg Terminal, Node, Typescript.
Java/Kotlin	5		<b>★★★☆</b>	Enterprise Java, Android, JNI, Web-Applets, Tomcat
Windows	10+		****	Since 3.0, Internals, SDK, GDI/+, COM/+
Web	5+		★★★☆☆	ASP.Net, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Frameworks
Unix	3 .		★★★☆☆	AIX, Solaris, Linux; Darwin (MacOS), Bloomberg
Cloud	5		***	AWS, Infrastructure, Computing, Serverless, VPCs, CI/CD
Databases	10+	<u>-\\</u>	****	Design, DDL, Data Tier, SQL, NoSQL, Desktop
TCP/IP	3		<b>★★★☆</b>	SSH, SSL/TLS; WS_FTP - fastest FTP client at the time
AWS	5		★★★☆☆	DynamoDB, SQS, EC2, S3, Lamda, CDK, Route 53, many
IPTV	5		★★★☆☆	ASP.Net MRML to set-top-box, VHO integration

While I do not claim to maintain focused expertise in all the above simultaneously, I have a strong inventory of current and refreshable skills and solution finding experience. The table above is my attempt to estimate and depict for each skill my:

⋄ accumulated experience; ⋄ engagement over time; ⋄ overall self rating.

 $I\ look\ forward\ to\ the\ opportunity\ to\ demonstrate\ my\ skills,\ and\ contribute\ positively\ to\ your\ organization.\ ^*Combined\ over\ time.$ 

Aspects				
Multi-Sector	Experience in Financial, Healthcare, Education, Defense, Internet, TV, and other industries.			
Travel/Consulting	Traveling for trade shows, client meetings, collaboration, and recruiting.			
User Experience	UX/UI designing, building, testing including for limited input devices such as phones and TVs.			
Multimedia	Programming, encoding, decoding, and delivering image, video, and music formats.			
Algorithms	Efficiently identifying and applying the appropriate algorithms and data structures.			
Team Lead	Experience and recognition as team lead, principal developer, guide, and mentor.			
low level coding	Coding at the bit level, endianness, protocols, layouts, MIL-STD-1553, Arduino, etc.			

Education	References
BSc in Computer Science with Math Minor Georgia State University	linkedin.com/in/arizona-edwards#recommendations

## **Work Experience**

#### **Amazon**

Software Development Engineer II

Dec 2016 to Feb 2023

I used Java, Kotlin, and several AWS technologies (DynamoDB, SQS, Elasticsearch, Lambda, etc.) to develop cloud based services that were part of a very large-scale invoice-processing and accounting application.

I was responsible (primary service owner) for the Accounting service for a long time, delivered training sessions and wikis on accounting concepts, and worked closely with analysts in workshops with other organizations to translate their needs into software requirements.

I used infrastructure-as-code to architect and deploy the service with multi-zone redundancy and data security.

I contributed to hiring, being involved in over 200 hiring decisions including travel to hiring events, interviews, and phone screens.

**Bloomberg** Senior Software Engineer Jun 2013 to Jun 2016

I designed, implemented, and supported enterprise data solutions regarding fixed income securities.

I programmed mostly in and for the Unix command line environment, primarily in C++, SQL and Python, along with Fortran, JavaScript, shell languages and many Bloomberg proprietary technologies.

I did user interface development, working on several screens in the Bloomberg Terminal, including customer facing screens.

I was substantially involved in and responsible for database design and programming, feasibility and technical reviews, coding, all stages of testing, documentation, sign off if required for UX/security/compliance, phased rollout, configuration, and ultimately support and on-call.

I developed and enhanced parts of the "snap-shot" infrastructure that captures market data at critical moments for major market centers around the world including New York, London, Tokyo, and Australia.

I was the principal software engineer on the project to migrate the product we deliver to the Philadelphia Federal Reserve. I implemented the quality control and validation for the massive data files without any metadata by performing comparative analysis.

I developed functionality to configure and manage customer entitlement for efficient retrieval where customers subscribe to both particular securities (rows) and to particular fields (columns) about those securities.

## **Georgia Tech Research Institute**

Contract Programmer

Apr 2012 to May 2013

I was a key implementer of several successful electronic warfare test projects primarily using C++, C++/CLI, Python, and C#.

I developed and enhanced applications to monitor and control communications between devices over a MILSTD1553 serial interface and display real-time visualizations of the traffic.

I designed and developed an AN/APR-39 (Radar Warning System) simulator that could communicate with a physical AN/AAR-47 (Laser Warning System) and emulate and test the protocols for startup, version detection, and control/display integration for aircraft with both systems.

I directed and coached the two student interns on my project, and indirectly provided additional mentoring to other student interns.

I conceived of and successfully implemented a small hardware project with integrated circuits (ICs) and electronic components that allowed programmatic control of the test rack for unsupervised, overnight testing.

I used code structure, self documenting code, and the .Net reflection capabilities of Managed C++ to extract metadata about the meanings of bits and bit sets so that even in hexadecimal and binary raw data views, I show tooltips with interpretive information when the mouse hovers over data.

Alcatel-Lucent Solution Line Manager May 2009 to Mar 2012

Implemented software solutions for IPTV television and telephone service providers using primarily C#, SQL, Java, SQL and JavaScript.

Activities included travel all around the world and in the US for collaboration, customer interaction, trade-shows, conferences etc. including to Singapore, India, Poland, England, Belgium, and Silicon Valley, and I acted as a liaison to development teams outside the US.

I created an Android application and prototyped several set-top-box applications to showoff Mediaroom integration and capabilities including a Pandora client, instant messaging, and a local cinema times browser.

I worked inside customer VHOs (Video Head-end Offices), labs, and data centers installing and configuring racks, blades, NICs, SANs, fiber, Multi-Path IO, VMs, Windows and Linux Servers, clusters, and custom software in various network architectures.

### **Additional Work Experience**

For additional and more detailed work experience, please see my cv website at <a href="https://budu.co/cv">https://budu.co/cv</a> or download PDF versions from <a href="https://budu.co/cv/download.html">https://budu.co/cv/download.html</a>.

I have additional experience in Healthcare, Education, Banking, Internet, and boxed retail software. I also have experience in television (IPTV) and multimedia programming.